although
i call raymond ho
thank you mr speaker i rise to take a
call to support this bill especially
delivered by the minister in the chair
and this is a sensible bill and we will
be supporting it through
to the committee stage
to to the select committee the bill
makes a number of technical amendments
to the prudential
regulatory framework for the insurance
industry
the insurance prudential supervision
act 2010 received the royal ascent on
the 7th of september 2010.
it established
licensing and prudential supervision
regime for insurers carrying on
insurance business in new zealand
in other words insurers carry on
insurance business in new zealand are
required by the act to participate in a
licensing and prudential supervision
regime
there is a transitional period under the
act and
that rhymes through to the 7th of
september 2013. most insurers carry on
business during the provincial
period are operating under a provincial
license whereby the full effect of the
act is delayed while insurers follow a
path
to full
compliance
at the end of the transitional period
all professional licenses will have
expired
needless to say that this bill needs to
be enacted before that date and this
bill should have had its first reading
month ago
through the licensing phase of the 2010
act a number of technical issues have
been identified as appropriate
for reform this bill brings amendments
relating to those technical issues
the key amendments proposed under this
bill included
firstly requiring the reserve bank to
keep a register of licensed insurers
secondly allowing overseas insurers to
report with the reserve bank's consent
entering financial information that
complies with home jurisdiction
requirements rather than new zealand
international
financial reporting standards ga ap
and thirdly
extending the term of professional
licenses of insurers
that enter into an insolvency procedure
before the 7th of september
2013.
extending the term of the provincial
licenses of those insurers would make
sure
that the distress management tools
made available and part four
of the act remain available to the
reserve bank and liquidators
it is intended that the amendments
proposed and
this bill will come into force before
the 7th of september 2013
however
this has yet to be confirmed or cannot
get confirmed because
it only had its first reading tonight
uh julian genter thank you mr speaker i
rise to take a call on the first reading
of the